Caffè Lena collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 8: Finances, bills, and management
    - Payroll, 1989-1991, undated (Box-folder 12/3)
      Forms and documentation from New York State Department of Labor, U.S. Department of the Treasury, payroll reconciliation, W-4 forms, tax papers, etc.
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 1 of 8), October 1989 (Box-folder 12/4)
      Includes documents regarding expenses, petty cash reconciliation sheets, table checks, etc.
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 2 of 8), November 1989 (Box-folder 12/5)
      See note for 12/4.
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 3 of 8), December 1989 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 4 of 8), January 1990 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 5 of 8), February 1990 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 6 of 8), July 1991 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 7 of 8), August 1991 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Caffè Lena monthly records (folder 8 of 8), September 1991 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Caffè Lena: bank statements and cancelled checks, 1985-1989, undated (Box-folder 13/4)
      Includes check books, bank statements, deposit slips, and cancelled checks. Also includes Social Security documents, and a handwritten, folded chart dated January 1989 with a breakdown of payments per institution.
    - Caffè Lena Trust Fund, 1989 (Box-folder 13/5)
      Documentation, including correspondence, bank checks, etc., regarding the fund set up to keep Caffè Lena in business following Lena Spencer's fall and subsequent heart attack.
    - Caffè Lena Trust Fund: trust agreement and related documents, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 13/6)
      Includes a photocopy of the trust agreement, a proposed management plan for the Caffè Lena Trust, a form letter to supporters, etc.
    - Caffè Lena Trust Fund: bank statements and cancelled checks, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 13/7)
      From Adirondack Trust Co.
    - Key Bank: check books, statements, etc., 1989-1990 (Box-folder 14/1)
      Includes check books, statements, cancelled checks, etc., for the Lena Spencer Trust Fund.
    - ASCAP and BMI: agreements, statements, and reports, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Bills and statements (folder 1 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Bills and statements (folder 2 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box-folder 14/4)
      See note for folder 14/3.
    - Budget reconciliation documents, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Employee resignation and statement from the trustees read at the press conference, 1989 (Box-folder 14/6)
      Includes copies of the resignation letter signed by five Caffè Lena employees, and the statement given in the name of the trustees at a press conference.
    - Manager's log, circa 1990s (Box-folder 14/7)
      Spiral notebook with lined paper, filled with handwritten notes, and a few preprinted or handwritten pieces of paper added.
    - Food service permits and related documentation, 1986-1989, undated (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Caffè Lena co-operative, circa 1989 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Caffè Lena: statistics, budget, and meeting notes, 2005 (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Subseries 9: Manuscripts that accompanied sound recordings and moving image items, 2005
    Manuscript materials from tape boxes, cassettes, etc. Includes clippings set lists, notes, etc. Not all audiovisual items were accompanied by manuscripts.
    - SR001-SR060 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - SR088-SR430 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - SR431-SR502 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - MV13, MV17, MV18, MV26 (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Subseries 10: Sound recording containers and manuscript materials that accompanied them (photocopies)
    - SR001-SR030 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - SR031-SR060 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - SR061-SR090 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - SR091-SR120 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - SR121-SR211 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - SR212-SR269 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - SR270-SR355 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - SR356-SR420 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - SR421-SR438 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - SR439-SR523 (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Subseries 11: Oversize manuscript materials
    - Media coverage, circa 1972-1991 (Box-folder 17/1-3)
      Three folders of clippings and sections from local and national newspapers plus an issue of Life magazine with a letter to the editor by Lena Spencer. The newspaper clippings are about Lena Spencer, Caffè Lena, and related news.
  - Subseries 12: Scrapbooks and related materials
    - Scrapbook from Dallas Cline (Box 18)
      Contents were assembled from old folk music posters and flyers, and not mounted to the pages. Approximately 100 manuscript items, and two photographic items (black and white prints).
    - Square scrapbook, 1960s-2001, Approximately 12 in. x 12 in. (Box 19)
      Metal spiral-bound scrapbook, with newspaper magazine clippings and printouts of digital photos on paper, mounted on heavy black paper pages. Topics range across Caffè Lena's history. About 20 pages, most with multiple items mounted on them.
    - Guest register for a Caffè Lena exhibit, Approximately 10 in. x 10 in. (Box 19)
      Metal spiral-bound scrapbook. Decorated guest register for an exhibit marking Caffè Lena's 45th anniversary. Three pages of signatures (one is a loose page); only one pages is filled with names and addresses.
    - Scrapbook without a spine, 2005, Approximately 14 in. x 11 in. (Box 20)
      Most of the spine is missing. Contents include programs and documentation from various Caffè Lena theatrical productions, as newspaper articles, correspondence, and seemingly unrelated materials. Approximately 40 pages, with one or more items affixed to one side of each page.
    - Caffè Lena Theatre scrapbook, Approximately 11 1/2 in. x 11 in. (Box 20)
      Three-ring notebook with denim-like cover, containing the playbill, reviews, and photos related to the Caffè Lena production of Juno and the Paycock, by Sean O'Casey (directed by Edward Reich).
    - Scrapbook celebrating Hattie Austin (Miss Hattie), October-November 1978, 8 1/2 in. x 11 in. (Box 20)
      Loose pages with clippings, correspondence, and photos honoring Miss Hattie, who founded Hattie's Chicken Shack, a Saratoga Springs institution.
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  The ID number SR479 is not assigned to any item.
  - Subseries 1: Andy and Bill Spence collection
    - Caffè Lena benefit: Michael Cooney, Sandy and Caroline Paton, Smoke Dawson, Molly Scott, Des and Juliet Rainey, Tom Paxton, Greenbriar Boys, February 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR001)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0001. This may be the Sunday night recording.
    - Caffè Lena benefit: Greenbriar Boys, Billy Faier, Happy and Artie Traum, Barbara Dane, Don McLean, Pennywhistlers, Sonya Malkine, February 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR002)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0002. This may be the Saturday night recording.
    - Michael Cooney, Bill Vanaver, February 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 and 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR010)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0010.
    - Don McLean and other artists, March 8, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips and 3 3/4 ips, 1/4 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR023)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0023. Tape jumps around between artists.
    - Rosalie Sorrels, August 2, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR004)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0004.
    - Lou Killen; parts of Don McLean and Tom Winslow sets, October 26, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 and 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR005)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0005.
    - Hedy West, November 9, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR007)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0007.
    - Jerry Jeff Walker, David Bromberg (1 of 2), December 14, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR008)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0008.
    - Jerry Jeff Walker, David Bromberg (2 of 2), December 14, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR009)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0009.
    - Don McLean, December 21, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR006)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0006.
    - Don McLean; Shirley's 78 rpm records; excerpt of a Michael Cooney set, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog,, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR003)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0003.
    - Best of Caffè Lena 1968: includes Don McLean, Lou Killen, Rosalie Sorrels, Steve Gillette, Jerry Jeff Walker/David Bromberg, Bill Spence/Jack Hume, Michael Cooney, and Hedy West, 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR018)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0018. Compilation of previously transferred tapes.
    - Patrick Sky; Paul Geremia (Side B), April 26, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR015)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0015.
    - Happy and Artie Traum, June 14, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR014)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0014.
    - Jean Ritchie (2nd set), September 20, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR013)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0013. First set described in engineer's transfer notes as "not available."
    - Ray Bierl, Alan Stowell (guest set: Frank Dubin, Andy Cohen, Kurt Anderson, Bill Hinkley), September 28, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR011)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0011.
    - Fran and Gilles (with Gary Pouge, Willie Dobson, Nano Riley, Alan Stowell), November 6 or 9, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, stereo; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR012)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0012. The date is unconfirmed.
    - Steve Gillette, November 16, 1969, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR028)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0028.
    - Kate McGarrigle and Roma Baron; various artists. Side B features Woody Guthrie tribute, including Lena Spencer, Michael Cooney, Don McLean, February 22, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR022)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0022.
    - Sorry Muthas, Bill Spence with Alan Stowell and Bill Hinkley, July 19, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, stereo; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR021)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0021.
    - Guy Carawan, Saul Broudy (with Alan Stowell and Kurt Anderson), April 14, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR017)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0017.
    - Bill Vanaver, April 18, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR016)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0016.
    - Don McLean, Frank Wakefield (four instrumentals, with Don on backup guitar), August 22, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR024)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0024
    - Don McLean, September 19, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR025)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0025. Recorded at an unidentified venue in Albany, New York.
    - Jeff Guthrie, Buster Jackson, Arlo Guthrie, John Pilla, Frank Wakefield, October 11, 1970, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR026)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0026. Guest vocals by Lena Spencer.
    - At Caffè Lena: Side A: David Bromberg and his Fabulous Torpedos (Steve Berg, bass; Will Scarlett, harmonica). Side B: Gordon Bok, December 5, 1970 (Side A); November 14, 1970 (Side B), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR029)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0029. The log for ABS B2 0001 matches the information for this recording.
    - Mike Seeger, Rosalie Sorrels, Bill Spence, March 21, 1971, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR027)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0027. The tape box also credits Sara Grey.
    - Hedy West, Rosalie Sorrels, Frank Wakefield, Ray Burrell, and two unidentified artists, November 20, 1971 (Side A); November 28, 1971 (Side B), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 2 track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR035)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0035. The log for ABS B2 0007 matches the information for this recording.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: Patrick Sky and Liam O’Flynn. Side B: Frank Wakefield and Ellen Kierney, December 3, 1971 (Side A); December 11, 1971 (Side B), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR033)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0033. The log for ABS B2 0005 matches the information for this recording.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: The High Level Ranters (fiddle tunes). Side B: Utah Phillips, 1971, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips and 3 3/4 ips, two track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR030)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0030. The log for ABS B2 0002 matches the information for this recording. Side A is dated 1971.
    - Paul Geremia (January 4, 1972) and David Bromberg (January 21, 1972), Patrick Sky (December 3, 1971), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR036)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0036. The log for ABS B2 0008 matches the information for this recording. The recording of Patrick Sky was dubbed from ABS B2 0005. David Bromberg at Caffè Lena with Steven Berg on bass, and Jack Hume on dobro during the second set. Guest performance by Joel Zoss before second set. One song from a Patrick Sky set at the beginning of other side of tape (recorded at 7.5 ips, 1⁄4 track mono, dubbed from ABS B2 0005
    - Bottle Hill, and Dave and Toni Arthur, April 9, 1972, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR032)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0032 (box is labeled ABS B2 0004).
    - "Welcome to Caffè Lena" master tape: includes Pete Seeger, Utah Phillips, Rosalie Sorrels, and Michael Cooney, 1972, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR020)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0020. Duplicate.
    - Dolby "B" of "Welcome to Caffè Lena" master tape: Michael Cooney, Bill Vanaver, Paul Geremia, Bob and Evelyn Beers, Lou Killen, High Level Ranters, Rosalie Sorrels, Patrick Sky, Bottle Hill, Hedy West, Utah Phillips, Lena Spencer, Frank Wakefield, circa 1972, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR019)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0019.
    - Live from Caffè Lena: Side A: Elizabeth Stuart (with Sara Grey). Side B: dubs of Doc Watson - Vanguard Records and Folklore, circa 1973, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR031)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0031. The log for ABS B2 0003 matches the information for this recording.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Bruce Phillips and Bill Vanaver, February 12, 2012, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, two track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR034)
      Original item ID: ABS B1 0034. The log for ABS B2 0006 matches the information for this recording. Includes two sets per artist.
  - Subseries 2: WAML collection (John Nazarenko and Alan Bartenhagen)
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Dave Van Ronk (January 2, 1988) and beginning of Rude Girls (#2, #3) (June 10, 1988); interview with Lena Spencer (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR038)
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Dave Van Ronk; Rude Girls, January 1988, 1 videocassette (VHS): digital audio (no video content). (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR527)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0010.
    - Bill Staines (part 2 of 2) and Patty Larkin (part 1 of 2), January 20, 1989, 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR044)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0019. DAT 13 and 14 may be the designations for copies of this recording.
    - Live at Lena's: Steve Gillette, Cindy Mangsen, Rosalie Sorrels, Lena Spencer (interview regarding Rosalie Sorrels), February 25, 1989, 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR041)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0016. The Rosalie Sorrels set is the same as on DK B4 0021 and 0022. More than one recording date; only February 25, 1989, is documented.
    - Live at Lena's: Rosalie Sorrels, Lena Spencer (interview regarding Rosalie Sorrels) (February 25, 1989); Aztec Two-Step (May 27, 1989), 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR042)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0017. The Rosalie Sorrels set is the same as on DK B4 0021 and 0022. Interview with Lena probably continued from SR041.
    - Live at Lena's: Rosalie Sorrels, February 25, 1989, 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR523)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0006.
    - Caffè Lena documentary, by Stephen Trombley, 1989, 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR529)
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): John McCutcheon (July 19, 1991); Tom Chapin (July 19, 1991; September 24, 1991), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR518)
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Gamble Rogers [undated]; Cindy Mangsen, Steve Gillette (November 6, 1991), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR524)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0007. One of Gamble Rogers's last performances.
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): June Tabor and Mark Emerson (aired December 4, 1991); Michael Jerling, Tony Markellis (aired January 1, 1992), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR520)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0003.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Tom Chapin, Steve Gillette, Cindy Mangsen, 1991 or after, 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR049)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0024. "Song for Gamble" would have been for Gamble Rogers, who died October 10, 1991.
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Heavenly Tones (February 5, 1992); Pierce Pettis (March 4, 1992), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR519)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0002.
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Margaret MacArthur, with her daughter Megan and son Dan (April 1, 1992); Dave Van Ronk (May 6, 1992), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR526)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0009.
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Patty Larkin (June 3, 1992); highlights compilation - year in review/various artists (July 1, 1992), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR521)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0004. Barbara Harris introduces each performer: John McCutcheon, Gamble Rogers, Michael Jerling, Tony Markellis, Steve Gillette, Cindy Mangsen, June Tabor, Mark Emerson, Pierce Pettis, Tom Chapin, Patty Larkin, Dave Van Ronk.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Rude Girls (September 2, 1992) and Schooner Fare (October 7, 1992), 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR039)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0014. SR039 and SR525 may be the same recording (one may be original and the other a copy).
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Rude Girls (September 2, 1992); Schooner Fare (October 7, 1992), 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR525)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0008. SR039 and SR525 may be the same recording (one may be original and the other a copy).
    - At Caffè Lena: Rosalie Sorrels and Paul Geremia, January 1, 1993, 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR037)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0012. Noted on documentation: DAT #1 and cassette #1.
    - Live at Lena's: Rosalie Sorrels and Paul Geremia (#1), January 1993, 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR528)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0011.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: Pierce Pettis. Side B: John McCutcheon, 1 sound cassette (100 min.): analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR040)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0015. Same show as the recording on SR047 (WAML B3 0022).
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: Pierce Pettis. Side B: John McCutcheon, 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR047)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0022. DAT 18: Pierce Pettis. DAT 19: John McCutcheon. See note for SR040.
    - Rosalie Sorrels reminisces about Lena, performs "Twas On a Night Like This" with a backing band, 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR043)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0018. Recording is only about 8 minutes long.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: Patty Larkin, John McCutcheon. Side B: Various artists (John McCutcheon, Michael Jerling and Tony Markellis, Cindy Mangsen and Steve Gillette, June Tabor and Mark Emerson), 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR045)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0020. DAT 15: June Tabor and Mark Emerson. DAT 16: Michael Jerling and Tony Markellis.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: June Tabor and Mark Emerson. Side B: Michael Jerling and Tony Markellis, 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR046)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0021.
    - Live at Caffè Lena: Side A: John McCutcheon, Tom Chapin. Side B: John McCutcheon, 1 sound cassette: analog, stereo. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR048)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0023. DAT 19: John McCutcheon. DAT 20: Tom Chapin.
    - Live at Lena's (two shows): Aztec Two-Step; Bill Staines, 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR522)
      Original item ID: WAML B3 0005.
    - Caffè Lena, 1 sound videocassette (VHS): digital. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR530)
  - Subseries 3: 20th Anniversary (John Nazarenko collection)
    - Robin and Linda Williams, Lena proclamation, Bill Staines, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR050)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0003.
    - Bill Staines; Margaret MacArthur and family, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR051)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0004. The MacArthur family includes Margaret's children: Megan playing bass, Gary playing fiddle, Dan playing guitar.
    - Margaret MacArthur and family, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR052)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0005. See note for SR051.
    - Robin and Linda Williams, Kate and Anna McGarrigle, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR053)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0006.
    - Robin and Linda Williams, Lena Spencer, Dave Van Ronk, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR054)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0007.
    - Arlo Guthrie with Shenandoah, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips and 3 3/4 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR055)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0008. Last song recorded at 3.75 ips, machine recalibrated for transfer of last song.
    - Nick Seeger, Michael Cooney, David Bromberg, May 21, 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half track, stereo; 10 in. (Item id AFC 2009/035: SR056)
      Original item ID: 20th B4 0009.